[
    {
        "tlk_id": 15,
        "tile1": 84,
        "x_pos1": 1,
        "y_pos1": 20,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Little Jon",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A singing bard.",
            "job": "I sing of Britannia.",
            "heal": "Quite well indeed!",
            "keyword1": "BRIT",
            "keyword2": "EART",
            "answer1": "Britannia is a land so fair, to other lands I would not dare!",
            "answer2": "I hope someday thou may return!",
            "yesnoquestion": "I hear that thou art from another world?",
            "yesanswer": "What is it called?",
            "noanswer": "Just a rumor."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 14,
        "tile1": 87,
        "x_pos1": 8,
        "y_pos1": 15,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Asemly",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A short jester.",
            "job": "I am here to serve thee.",
            "heal": "Jolly good.",
            "keyword1": "SERV",
            "keyword2": "DANC",
            "answer1": "Well, I can dance and sing!",
            "answer2": "And sing, tra la la...",
            "yesnoquestion": "Does that interest thee?",
            "yesanswer": "Good!",
            "noanswer": "Well then, I guess I'm no help at all then."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 13,
        "tile1": 37,
        "x_pos1": 5,
        "y_pos1": 6,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Lady Tessa",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A wise lady.",
            "job": "I am the keeper.",
            "heal": "Well.",
            "keyword1": "KEEP",
            "keyword2": "MYST",
            "answer1": "I cannot say.",
            "answer2": "Mystics can be found by an eight parts avatar!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Hast thou attained enlightenment in all eight virtues?",
            "yesanswer": "The mystic weapons lie in the training room of Serpent castle!",
            "noanswer": "Alas."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 12,
        "tile1": 37,
        "x_pos1": 5,
        "y_pos1": 5,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Sir Simon",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A wise lord.",
            "job": "I am the keeper.",
            "heal": "I am fine.",
            "keyword1": "KEEP",
            "keyword2": "MYST",
            "answer1": "Of what I cannot say!",
            "answer2": "Mystics can be found by an eight parts avatar!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Hast thou attained enlightenment in all eight virtues?",
            "yesanswer": "The mystic armour lies in the center of the oak grove!",
            "noanswer": "Alas."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 11,
        "tile1": 91,
        "x_pos1": 14,
        "y_pos1": 11,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 4,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Pix",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A small girl.",
            "job": "What's a job?",
            "heal": "Good, thanks.",
            "keyword1": "A   ",
            "keyword2": "A   ",
            "answer1": "A",
            "answer2": "A",
            "yesnoquestion": "And thee?",
            "yesanswer": "Good.",
            "noanswer": "Too bad."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 10,
        "tile1": 44,
        "x_pos1": 1,
        "y_pos1": 30,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Barren",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A hooded ranger.",
            "job": "I travel the land.",
            "heal": "I am well.",
            "keyword1": "LAND",
            "keyword2": "RUNE",
            "answer1": "Britannia.",
            "answer2": "Search the hills in the south-east corner of town!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou dim?",
            "yesanswer": "I thought so.",
            "noanswer": "We shall see."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 9,
        "tile1": 47,
        "x_pos1": 22,
        "y_pos1": 31,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 4,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Wheatpin",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A meek shepherd.",
            "job": "I just sit here.",
            "heal": "Fine.",
            "keyword1": "RUNE",
            "keyword2": "A   ",
            "answer1": "Around there in the nook of the mountains!",
            "answer2": "A",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou looking for something?",
            "yesanswer": "What?",
            "noanswer": "I see."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 8,
        "tile1": 39,
        "x_pos1": 6,
        "y_pos1": 25,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Damsel",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A small druid.",
            "job": "I am here to buy food.",
            "heal": "A bit hungry.",
            "keyword1": "FOOD",
            "keyword2": "RATI",
            "answer1": "Yes, I hear they have the best rations here.",
            "answer2": "Rations are used in dungeons.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou travel in the depths?",
            "yesanswer": "In the great castle there is a secret entrance!",
            "noanswer": "Probably a wimp."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 7,
        "tile1": 36,
        "x_pos1": 9,
        "y_pos1": 5,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Sir Hobie",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A tall muscular knight.",
            "job": "I serve Lord British.",
            "heal": "Tired and hungry but always faithful.",
            "keyword1": "FAIT",
            "keyword2": "QUES",
            "answer1": "I quest always for Britannia!",
            "answer2": "My quest is to defeat the evils of the world.",
            "yesnoquestion": "'tis thy quest also?",
            "yesanswer": "We are as one.",
            "noanswer": "A shame it is!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 6,
        "tile1": 32,
        "x_pos1": 12,
        "y_pos1": 2,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Jingles",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A young mage!",
            "job": "I seek the wisdom of magic.",
            "heal": "Fine.",
            "keyword1": "MAGI",
            "keyword2": "MAST",
            "answer1": "My master knows the gate travel spell!",
            "answer2": "My master is Mentorian.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou know him?",
            "yesanswer": "Good.",
            "noanswer": "He lives in a hidden village in Lock Lake reachable only by ship, ask of the gate spell!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 5,
        "tile1": 82,
        "x_pos1": 23,
        "y_pos1": 8,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Sal",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A very large woman.",
            "job": "I am the barmaid I serve the ale!",
            "heal": "Stronger every day!",
            "keyword1": "ALE ",
            "keyword2": "BREW",
            "answer1": "We have the finest brew in Britannia!",
            "answer2": "We serve only Folley on tap!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou favor Folley?",
            "yesanswer": "A great mug if I may say so!",
            "noanswer": "Too bad, it's the best!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 4,
        "tile1": 32,
        "x_pos1": 20,
        "y_pos1": 6,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Zair the Wise",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A man of many years.",
            "job": "I've been near the codex!",
            "heal": "Well.",
            "keyword1": "CODE",
            "keyword2": "WORD",
            "answer1": "Its secrets are boundless!",
            "answer2": "A three part key and a word of passage are needed to enter the chamber. Ask my brother beyond Lock Lake of the word!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Seen it?",
            "yesanswer": "Wow!",
            "noanswer": "Seek it!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 3,
        "tile1": 36,
        "x_pos1": 27,
        "y_pos1": 8,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Sven",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A tall burly man.",
            "job": "I'm a lumberjack, ya.",
            "heal": "Fine, thanks.",
            "keyword1": "LUMB",
            "keyword2": "AXE ",
            "answer1": "Wit' my axe, I can chop'm down quick, ya.",
            "answer2": "It's a big axe, ya.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art ya a lumberjack?",
            "yesanswer": "Good for you, ya.",
            "noanswer": "Build up those arms, ya!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 2,
        "tile1": 82,
        "x_pos1": 27,
        "y_pos1": 25,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Francesca",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A tough girl.",
            "job": "I am the stable hand.",
            "heal": "Right good.",
            "keyword1": "STAB",
            "keyword2": "SMIT",
            "answer1": "I saw the way ya dealt with ol' Red Eye!",
            "answer2": "The talking horse!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Ya haven't come to steal a horse I hope?",
            "yesanswer": "Well the master ain't gonna like that much!",
            "noanswer": "Then must be to see Smith!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 82,
        "x_pos1": 17,
        "y_pos1": 25,
        "move": 128,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 80,
        "x_pos1": 9,
        "y_pos1": 13,
        "move": 0,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 93,
        "x_pos1": 23,
        "y_pos1": 22,
        "move": 1,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 21,
        "x_pos1": 27,
        "y_pos1": 20,
        "move": 1,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 20,
        "x_pos1": 26,
        "y_pos1": 22,
        "move": 1,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 15,
        "y_pos1": 17,
        "move": 0,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 22,
        "y_pos1": 13,
        "move": 0,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 92,
        "x_pos1": 22,
        "y_pos1": 21,
        "move": 255,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 16,
        "tile1": 20,
        "x_pos1": 30,
        "y_pos1": 20,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 0,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Smith",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A white stallion",
            "job": "Oh, not much.",
            "heal": "Good, good.",
            "keyword1": "A   ",
            "keyword2": "A   ",
            "answer1": "A",
            "answer2": "A",
            "yesnoquestion": "A",
            "yesanswer": "A",
            "noanswer": "A"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 83,
        "x_pos1": 6,
        "y_pos1": 3,
        "move": 128,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 83,
        "x_pos1": 15,
        "y_pos1": 8,
        "move": 128,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 82,
        "x_pos1": 25,
        "y_pos1": 4,
        "move": 1,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 82,
        "x_pos1": 22,
        "y_pos1": 4,
        "move": 1,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 82,
        "x_pos1": 7,
        "y_pos1": 27,
        "move": 128,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 1,
        "tile1": 80,
        "x_pos1": 4,
        "y_pos1": 16,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Wilmoore",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A very big guard.",
            "job": "I am the chief guard in the village of Paws!",
            "heal": "Excellent.",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "TROU",
            "answer1": "Paws is a great village and we keep it safe!",
            "answer2": "Pirates come from an isle to the east!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou mean to cause trouble?",
            "yesanswer": "Then thou had best leave!",
            "noanswer": "Good."
        }
    }
]